{"Topic": "Government Schemes", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "What is the minimum pension guaranteed by the Govt of India under the Atal Pension Yojana?", "op1": "Rs. 1,000", "op2": "Rs. 2,000", "op3": "Rs. 3,000", "op4": "Rs. 5,000", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "What is the minimum age at which a subscriber can join the Atal Pension Yojana?", "op1": "25 years", "op2": "22 years", "op3": "18 years", "op4": "15 years", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What is the maximum age at which a subscriber can join the Atal Pension Yojana?", "op1": "30 years", "op2": "40 years", "op3": "50 years", "op4": "60 years", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is age at which subscriber will be eligible for pension under the Atal Pension Yojana?", "op1": "55 years", "op2": "57 Years", "op3": "58 years", "op4": "60 years", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What is the annual premium payable by the subscriber to the Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana?", "op1": "Rs. 210", "op2": "Rs. 330", "op3": "Rs. 450", "op4": "Rs. 510", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the insurance cover payable to the nominee on the death of the subscriber to the Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana?", "op1": "Rs. 50,000", "op2": "Rs. 1,00,000", "op3": "Rs. 1,50,000", "op4": "Rs. 2,00,000", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Entry to the Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana is not allowed after the age of -", "op1": "45 years", "op2": "50 years", "op3": "55 years", "op4": "60 years", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "What is the minimum age for joining the Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana?", "op1": "18 years", "op2": "21 years", "op3": "25 years", "op4": "30 years", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What is the age after which the benefit of insurance will not be available to the subscriber to the Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana?", "op1": "50 years", "op2": "55 years", "op3": "60 years", "op4": "65 years", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the amount payable to the subscriber on attaining the age of 55 years under the Pradhan Mantri Jeevan Jyoti Bima Yojana?", "op1": "Full amount subscribed", "op2": "Full amount subscribed with 4% interest", "op3": "50% of the amount subscribed", "op4": "No amount is payable", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "What is the annual premium payable under the Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana?", "op1": "Rs. 12", "op2": "Rs. 15", "op3": "Rs. 18", "op4": "Rs. 20", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "What is the insurance cover provided to the subscriber of the Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana in case of accidental death or full disability?", "op1": "Rs. 1,00,000", "op2": "Rs. 1,50,000", "op3": "Rs. 2,00,000", "op4": "Rs. 2,50,000", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the age group to whom the Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana is available?", "op1": "18 to 40 years", "op2": "18 to 50 years", "op3": "18 to 60 years", "op4": "18 to 70 years", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "What is the insurance cover provided to the subscriber of the Pradhan Mantri Suraksha Bima Yojana in case of partial disability?", "op1": "Rs. 1,00,000", "op2": "Rs. 1,50,000", "op3": "Rs. 2,00,000", "op4": "Rs. 2,50,000", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the overdraft allowed to the account holder after 6 months of satisfactory operation of Pradhan Mantri Jan Dhan Yojana account?", "op1": "Rs. 3000", "op2": "Rs. 5000", "op3": "Rs. 7000", "op4": "Rs. 10000", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the slogan of the Pradhan Mantri Jan Dhan Yojana?", "op1": "Sabka Saath Sabka Vikas", "op2": "Beti Bachao Beti Padhao", "op3": "Kal ki Fikr Nahin", "op4": "Mera Khata Bhagya Vidhata", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Upto what age of the girl child can an account under the Sukanya Samriddhi Yojana be opened?", "op1": "8 years", "op2": "9 years", "op3": "10 years", "op4": "12 years", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "For how many years can deposits be made in an account under the Sukanya Samriddhi Yojana?", "op1": "10 years", "op2": "12 years", "op3": "15 years", "op4": "21 years", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "What is the maximum number of accounts a natural or legal guardian can open for his girl children under the Sukanya Samriddhi Yojana?", "op1": "One", "op2": "Two", "op3": "Three", "op4": "Equal to the number of girl children", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the minimum annual deposit to be made in an account under the Sukanya Samriddhi Yojana?", "op1": "Rs. 1000", "op2": "Rs. 750", "op3": "Rs. 500", "op4": "Rs. 250", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What is the maximum amount that can be deposited in a year in an account under the Sukanya Samriddhi Yojana?", "op1": "Rs. 1,00,000", "op2": "Rs. 1,50,000", "op3": "Rs. 2,50,000", "op4": "Rs. 3,00,000", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What is the animal in the logo of Make in India campaign?", "op1": "Tiger", "op2": "Lion", "op3": "Elephant", "op4": "Cow", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which State has been allocated the maximum number of cities under the Smart Cities Mission?", "op1": "Uttar Pradesh", "op2": "Maharashtra", "op3": "Tamil Nadu", "op4": "Gujarat", "Answer": 3}]}